DANIEL C. TABION

Full-Stack Web Application Developer

847.899.2100

dctabion@gmail.com

http://www.dctabion.com

https://github.com/dctabion

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dctabion

SUMMARY

I am a web developer with strong analytical skills and experience with a variety of web frameworks, databases/ORMs, and front-end techniques. Through my successes as a music freelancer, I demonstrated a knack for client management/education, and requirements definition while displaying a tireless work ethic, meticulous attention to detail, and ability for creative problem solving.

TECH SKILLS

FRONTEND: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS. Materialize, Angular.js BACKEND: Express.js/Node.js , Ruby/Sinatra/Rails,. Active Record/postgresql, Mongo/Mongoose OTHER: Git/Github, Chrome Dev Tools, C-Programming

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Development Immersive Program, Oct 2015 – Jan 2016 General Assembly, Chicago, IL

Completed 12 week, full-time intensive program. Projects include:

- Flash Notes Note reading game played with digital piano that generates progress reports for teachers. Utilized Web MIDI API, Web Audio API, Mongoose/MongoDB, Express.js
- Chicago Towed Car Query Paired programming project. Utilizes City of Chicago Data API.
- Roach Rage an online video game created with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and jQuery
- The Specialist a group project that collects and shares crowd-sourced food and happy hour special information. Express.js/Node.js, Backbone.js, custom API.

Music Contractor/Freelancer, 2005-2015

- Live Music Production Consultant
 - Worked with clients to create customized live music package suitable for their events and within budget constraints.
 - o Coordinated logistics with event planners, venue managers, client and contract musicians.
- *Freelance Pianist* Performed in clubs, venues, festivals, private events with numerous groups in a myriad of styles.
- *Music Instructor* Created and followed protocols to manage client relationships. Managed personalized learning plans for students.

Software Engineer, Motorola, 1999 - 2005

Implemented bug fixes and new features for existing telecom server software. This included debugging, coding, creating/installing new software builds, regression testing, and using version control tools while adhering to our software development process.

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive, Oct 2015 – Jan 2016 General Assembly, Chicago, IL

BS Electrical Engineering, 1994 - 1998 Purdue University, W. Lafayette, IN